Guide to the Thomas J. Balcerski Acacia Fraternity papers, bulk 2006-2007
Balcerski, Thomas J. Acacia Fraternity papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Thomas J. Balcerski Acacia Fraternity papers, bulk 2006-2007
6853
Thomas J., Balcerski 1982-
4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Memorabilia, Movie Film, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers regarding research for the book Acacia Fraternity at Cornell: the first century.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers regarding research for the book Acacia Fraternity at Cornell: the first century.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Balcerski, Thomas J.,1982-; Acacia Fraternity--History.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also: Acacia Fraternity records, #37-4-1538
SERIES LIST
Series 1 - Research Materials
Box 1
Series II. Chapter Operations
Box 1
Series III. Chapter Operations
Boxes 2, 3
Series IV. Corporation
Box 3
Series V. Photographs
Box 3
Series VI. Research Multimedia
Box 4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I - Research Materials
  - Research Early Years, 1907-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research Later Years, World War II to the Wing, 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Research Middle Years, 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Research Recent Years, 1986-present (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Interview Notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Research Sources, Correspondences, and Ideas (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Williams’ Family Research (Chapter 5) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ECW and Hu Shi (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Copies of Deeds from County Clerk’s Office (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Wills from Surrogate Court (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Acacia Fraternity: The First Half Century by William S. Dye, Jr. (Photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Acacia: The Third Quarter Century by Delmer Goode (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cornelliana Misc. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - DKE at Cornell History (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Other Fraternity Histories (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Prairie School (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - History of the House Now at 303 E. Upland Road, Ithaca, NY (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fraternities without Brotherhood by Alfred McClung Lee (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series II - Composition and Production
  - Book Project - Author’s Personal Notes (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - History Project Promotional & Meeting Agendas and Minutes (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - History Project Communication (Internal) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - History Project Bills, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Permissions, Sales, and Other (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Library of Congress Information (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Production Information from Thomson-Shore (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Printers’ Quotes and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cornell Acacia Centennial Weblog, through February 2006, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Series III - Drafts and Proofs
  - Proof from Thomson-Shore Printer, July 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Early Drafts of Chapter 7, Prologue, and Notes (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Author’s Second Draft with Comments by TJB (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - May 1, 2007 "First" Draft with Comments by TJB (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Comments on Draft from Carol Kammen (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Comments on Drafts from Clara Y. Tow '07 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Bill Cammuso '92 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Comments on Draft by Bill Cammuso '92 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Draft with Comments by David Klesh '02 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with David Klesh '02 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Draft with Comments from Tim Thom '82 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cover Designs - Acacia History Project (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Final Draft - Sent to Printer July 25, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Author’s Third Draft with Index Notes (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Layout Mock-up with Comments (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Comments on Third Draft by Daniel Chazin, Copy Editor (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Review Draft by Sam Aronson, July 9, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Author’s Draft with Comments, July 13, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Draft with Commentary by Author, July 7, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Series IV - Centennial Weekend
  - Post-Centennial Correspondence and Acacia Fraternity at Cornell: The First Century Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Acacia Documentary Project (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Centennial/Book AFF Grant (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Planning (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Centennial Weekend Paperwork, August 24-26, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Centennial Merchandise (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Centennial Logo (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Centennial Registrations (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Centennial Weekend Materials (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Centennial Weekend Evaluations (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - History of Acacia Donors (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Centennial Horizons (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Inglis Family Recognition Day (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Awards Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Acacia Fraternity Records (#37-4-1538) Agreements (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Thomas J. Balcerski Acacia Fraternity Papers, Agreements, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence with Susan Chan Egan, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Jeremy Davis, Iowa State Chapter (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - History of Acacia Fraternity at Iowa State University, 1909-2009: Recollections of a Century of Brotherhood by George W. Gross, Harold D. Zarr, and Jeremy N. Davis, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Series V - Centennial Capital Campaign Papers
  - Advisory Board Minutes (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Planning and Projects (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Print Materials (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Stage 0 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Stage 1 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Stage 2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - AFF Funding and Policies (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Cornell University Capital Campaign Information (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Donors Lists - Acacia (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Reminder Letters (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Corporation Board Materials, 2007-2011 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Chapter Newsletter Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence with Steve Stein ’73 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Capital Campaign Invoices and Project Plans (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Capital Campaign Mailings and Donors, 2009-2012 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Syracuse-Cornell Summit, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Centennial+5 Planning (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Letter from William S. Dye, Jr, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Series VI - Research Multimedia
  - Acacia History Project Oral Interview Cassettes (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Acacia Fraternity, Cornell Chapter: 100 Years of Brotherhood (DVD) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Acacia Documentary Raw Footage, April 27, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Acacia Centennial DVD (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Centennial Weekend Photos, CD (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Acacia Sings Colorado Chapter, CD (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Acacia "Dream House" Maps, Plans, and Blueprints (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - History Center Photographs, CD (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Photographs taken from 35 mm slides by John Male (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Acacia Pictures from 1990s Albums (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Acacia Pictures (scans) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Acacia Scans, Small Pictures, July 4, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Acacia Scans, Large Pictures (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Acacia Travelers 1, CD (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Acacia Travelers 2, CD (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Acacia Files, Research, February 9, 2006-February 13, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Acacia History Materials, February 8, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Acacia House History Project, October 13, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Acacia Book Pics 1 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Acacia Book Pics 2 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - National Geographic Society: Directions Up, Down, All Around (featuring footage from Acacia chapter house) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Acacia Centennial Pictures by Andrew Brenner '91, August 24-26, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Acacia Documentary with Centennial (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Home Movies by James Symons '54, 1948-1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Days DVD by James Symons '54 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Acacia Centennial Capital Campaign Brochure (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Acacia DVD (Video shown at Centennial) (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Acacia Documentary Draft, July 2007 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Cassette tape interview with Bradley Ayres '06 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Cornell Acacia Centennial Fraternal Composite Services Footage Friday night (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Cornell Acacia Centennial Fraternal Composite Services Footage Saturday night and video (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Acacia Photographs (various) by Tom Balcerski (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Acacia Photographs (scans by Brad Ayres), 1990s (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Acacia Videos, ca. 2005 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Brian Kwoba Photo Session, November 11, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 35)